informa.com 2019-05-28

# Informa.com - Privacy Policy

## Introduction

As an international Business-to -Business Information Services Group, data and information is at the heart of what Informa does.

We take the privacy and protection of data and information seriously, and are committed to handling the personal information of all those we engage with, whether customers, suppliers, colleagues or any other community, responsibly and in a way that meets the legal requirements of the countries in which we operate.

This Privacy Policy relates to the information collected and processed by Informa when interacting with this website, [www.informa.com](http://www.informa.com/).

## About Informa ****

Informa PLC (“Informa”, “we”, “us” or “our”) is an international business-to-business Information Services Group. We serve commercial, professional and academic communities by helping them connect and learn, and by creating and providing access to content and intelligence that helps people and businesses work smarter and make better decisions faster

Informa comprises a number of legal entities organised into four operating divisions; Academic Publishing (which trades as the Taylor & Francis Group), Business Intelligence, Global Exhibitions and Knowledge and Networking (which trades as KNect365).

We operate in over 20 countries with varying data protection laws. Where there is a specific jurisdiction requirement, we provide information on how your personal information will be handled in that country and any additional rights that apply.

Informa is not responsible for personal data collected by its operating divisions. Each division maintains its own privacy policy with information on data is used, the legal basis for its use as well as outlining individual customer rights. This information is in the Privacy Policies of those divisional web pages and the pages of their associated companies and brands.

## What we collect ****

**This section explains the personal information that may be collected when using**[ **www.informa.com**](http://www.informa.com/) **or when contacting us.**

In this Privacy Policy, the term “personal information” refers to the types of information we may collect and use, which includes:

  * Contact details such as your name, email address, postal address and telephone number;
  * Professional background information;
  * Comments, feedback, posts and other content submitted; 
  * Interests and communication preferences including marketing permissions where appropriate;
  * Location information (e.g. the country in which you are based); and
  * IP address information and information relating to your use of the website.

We collect your personal information in the following main categories:

  * Website visitor data (e.g. analytics);
  * Subscriber data provided when signing up to news alerts; and
  * Contact data provided when asking general questions via the website.

### Sensitive personal data

If collecting or storing sensitive personal data, such as information relating to health, beliefs or political affiliation about customers, visitors and exhibitors, we will typically ask for your explicit consent.

### Children’s personal data

Our services and products are directed to academics and business professionals. They are not intended for children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal data from this age group. If any information is collected from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, it will be deleted.

## How and why personal information is used

**This section explains how and why we use personal information.**

### Lawful Processing in Europe

As we collect and use personal information, the lawful bases we use for this activity in Europe, as required under European data protection laws, are:

  * Where it is necessary for entering into or performing a contract with you
  * Where we have a legitimate interest to do so, provided your rights do not override these interests
  * Where you have consented to its use

### Website monitoring and analytics

We may use your personal information to analyse the use of our website content and services, in order to improve them, to develop new content and services and to predict future customer behaviour, as part of our legitimate interests as a commercial organisation.

### Enquiries

Any personal information provided on the Contact Us page will be used only to provide a response or to service the request or enquiry made. The information provided will not be added to the marketing or customer prospect databases of Informa’s operating divisions.

### News Alerts

The information collected when you sign up for News Alerts is used only to provide that service, and to understand the background and interests of our subscriber list.

In providing the service we gather statistics about how many emails are opened, using industry standard technologies including image downloads. This is to help us monitor and improve the news alerts service and information is collected and analysed at an aggregate level only.

With your permission, from time to time Informa may use your registration details to contact you about the news alerts service.

You can unsubscribe from the service at any time using links provided within our emails or by following this [link](https://informa.com/generic-content/news-alerts-unsubscribe/).

## How we protect personal information

**Any personal information given to us will be treated with the utmost care and security. This section sets out some of the security measures in place.**

A variety of physical and technical measures is used to keep data safe and prevent unauthorised access to, or use or disclosure of personal information.

Electronic data and databases are stored on secure computer systems and we control who has access to information, using both physical and electronic means. Our colleagues receive data protection training, and we have detailed security and data protection policies that colleagues are required to follow when handling personal data.

All reasonable steps are taken to ensure that your personal information is kept secure from unauthorised access, but we cannot guarantee it will be secure during the transmission process to this website because this transmission is not controlled by us.

### International transfer of personal information ****

As an international business and because of the technologies we use, personal information may be accessed by our colleagues and third-party service providers from locations outside of the European Economic Area, whose data protection laws may not be as extensive as those in Europe.

To ensure the same level of protection is in place when processing is conducted outside the European Economic Area, we use appropriate safeguards approved by the European Commission.

We apply appropriate protection to make sure your personal data remains adequately protected and is treated in line with this Policy. Informa has international data transfer agreements between its companies and with relevant third-party service providers based on standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file containing a user ID that is automatically placed on a computer or other device when visiting a website. Cookies record the pages visited and the actions taken on a website, but do not contain any personal information. From time to time, we may use cookies to administer the Website; track activity on the website; gather broad demographic information for aggregate use to improve the website, and to enable us to offer time-saving or personalised features on the website. For more information, see our Cookie Policy.

### Third-party links

This website contains links to other websites, including those of other companies within Informa.  These businesses will have their own privacy policies, tailored to their particular business practices and the sectors in which they operate, and if following those links, we recommend reviewing the privacy policy of each website to understand how personal data is used in that instance. The inclusion of links to these websites does not imply an endorsement or validation of their content, and we are not responsible for their privacy practices of, nor do we accept any liability in connection with the content on such websites.

## Who we share your personal information with

**As an international company, to provide you with services and products we may share your information for specific reasons. This section explains how and why we share personal data with other companies within Informa, suppliers and other third parties.**

Sharing with Informa Group companies  
We may share your personal information with certain other companies within Informa for specific purposes. For example, other Informa companies may assist in providing services to you or in carrying out internal analysis of the usage of products and services.

### Sharing with Service Providers

We may share your personal information with third parties to assist in providing products and services to you. These include website hosting/development providers, website analytics providers, email tracking service providers, cloud storage and cloud communication service providers and providers of other cloud software that enable us to provide the service. We will only share your personal information with such third parties to the extent necessary for them to provide such assistance.

### Sharing with other Organisations

We may share your personal information with third parties outside Informa in the event of a sale, merger, acquisition, partnership, joint venture, or negotiations related to the same with respect to all or part of our business.

In some circumstances, we may be legally required to disclose your personal information, because a court, the police, another judicial or law enforcement body, or government entity has asked us for it.

## How long information is kept

**We will only retain your personal information for as long as is necessary and as permitted by applicable laws.   **

We will retain your personal information while we are using it, as described in the section above and may continue to retain it after these uses have ended where we have a legitimate business purpose. For example, if you have opted out of marketing communications from us, we will retain limited details about you to ensure the opt-out request is honoured. We may also continue to retain your personal information to meet our legal requirements or to defend or exercise our legal rights.

The length of time for which we will retain personal information will depend on the purposes for which it is retained it. After we no longer need to retain your personal information, it will be deleted or securely destroyed.

## How to update your information and marketing preferences

**We want to ensure you remain in control of your personal information. We try to ensure that the personal information held about you is accurate and up-to-date, and will always give the opportunity to opt out of future marketing communications.**

Information on how to opt out will be given when your personal information is collected and specified on every marketing or news alert email sent. If at any stage you would like to update or correct such personal information, or opt-out of future marketing communications, email or write to us at the addresses provided in the ‘Contacting Us’ section below.

## Your Rights

**Informa operates in countries with data protection laws that may provide individuals the right to be able to access and control their information. We always will enable you to exercise those rights as provided by data protection laws.**

EU data protection laws give individuals a number of rights, where their data and information is processed by companies active and operating in Europe. Under General Data Protection Regulation these are:

  * The right to confirmation whether or not we have your personal data and, if we do, to obtain a copy of the personal information we hold. This is known as subject access request;
  * The right to have inaccurate data rectified;
  * The right to have your data erased. This does not however apply where it is necessary for us to continue to use the data for a lawful reason;
  * The right to request the restriction or suppression of their personal data, such as, we will stop using the data but we may continue storing it)
  * The right to obtain your personal data that you have provided to us, on the basis of consent or performance of a contract, and where technically feasible, transmitted in a common electronic format to you or directly to another company.
  * The right to object to the use of your data. Specifically, you have the right to object to our use for marketing and in relation to automated decision making, including profiling where there may be legal or similarly significant effects.

There are exceptions to the rights above. Where you make a request to us as part of these rights, we will always try to respond to your satisfaction, although there may be situations where we are unable to do so.

Depending on the laws of the country where you live, you may have other rights in respect of your personal information. If you wish to exercise any legal right in respect of your personal information, please contact us via one of the methods set out in the Contact Us section below.

In some cases, we may be entitled to decline a request you have made regarding your personal information, in accordance with application laws. We will explain if that is the case. Otherwise, we will meet your request as promptly as we reasonably can. If you have requested that we stop sending you marketing messages, please note that you may still receive them for a short period while the request is processed.

## Contact Us

**If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy you can contact our Group Data Protection Officer.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or relating to our use of your information, write to our Group Data Protection Officer at Informa PLC, 5 Howick Place, London, SW1P 1WG or email [GroupDPO@informa.com](mailto:GroupDPO@informa.com).

We hope to resolve any privacy concerns you may have. If you are not happy with our response, or you believe that your data protection or privacy rights have been infringed, you can complain to any supervisory authority or other public body with responsibility for enforcing privacy laws. In the UK, the UK Information Commissioner’s Office regulates and enforces data protection law. Their procedures can be found at [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

## Changes to Privacy Policy

To keep up with changing legislation, best practice and changes in how we process personal data, this Privacy Policy may be revised at any time without notice by posting an updated version on this website. Checking back periodically will mean you are aware of any changes. This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with the website’s Terms and is also subject to these Terms ([Click here to view the Terms & Conditions](https://informa.com/generic-content/terms--conditions/)).

This Privacy Policy was last updated on **12 Feb 2019**.
